[
  {
    "question": "How many books does the New Testament have?",
    "correctAnswer": "27",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "26",
      "66",
      "39"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000001"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah name her child?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Saul",
      "Samson",
      "Gideon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20",
    "id": "000002"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was responsible for the massacre of children in Bethlehem shortly after Jesus's birth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Herod",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Pilate",
      "The High Priest",
      "Quirinius"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 1",
    "id": "000003"
  },
  {
    "question": "Jesus healed Peter's mother-in-law. What was wrong with her?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fever",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Paralysis",
      "Blind in one eye",
      "Bleeding"
    ],
    "difficulty": 4,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1",
    "id": "000004"
  },
  {
    "question": "What promise do the meek receive from the Lord Jesus in the Beatitudes?",
    "correctAnswer": "They shall inherit the earth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "For them is the kingdom of heaven",
      "They shall be called children of God",
      "They shall see God"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:5",
    "id": "000005"
  },
  {
    "question": "What promise follows the Beatitude 'blessed are the pure in heart'?",
    "correctAnswer": "they shall see God",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "For them is the kingdom of heaven",
      "They shall be called children of God",
      "They shall inherit the earth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 5:8",
    "id": "000006"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet was not allowed to marry by the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jeremiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Jeremiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Jeremiah 16:2",
    "id": "000007"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet was commanded to marry by the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hosea",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Jeremiah",
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Hosea 1:2",
    "id": "000008"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet and his children were a symbol for Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Isaiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jeremiah",
      "Ezekiel",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Isaiah"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000009"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which prophet lost his wife during his time as a prophet?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ezekiel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaiah",
      "Jeremiah",
      "Hosea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 24:16-24",
    "id": "000010"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 1st day God created...",
    "correctAnswer": "the light",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "man",
      "plants",
      "fish"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:4",
    "id": "000011"
  },
  {
    "question": "On the 2nd day there was separation between...",
    "correctAnswer": "sea and sky",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "sea and land",
      "light and darkness",
      "light and land"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 1:6-8",
    "id": "000012"
  },
  {
    "question": "God rested on the...",
    "correctAnswer": "7th day",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1st day",
      "5th day",
      "6th day"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2:2",
    "id": "000013"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was the tree of the knowledge of good and evil?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the garden of Eden",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "In the garden of Aden",
      "Just outside the garden of Eden",
      "In Shinar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 2 and 3",
    "id": "000014"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was murdered by Cain?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "His mother",
      "His father",
      "Esau"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000015"
  },
  {
    "question": "How old was Methuselah when he died?",
    "correctAnswer": "969",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "996",
      "966",
      "669"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 5:27",
    "id": "000016"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long did Noah stay in the ark with his family?",
    "correctAnswer": "Just over a year",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "40 days",
      "7 months",
      "1.5 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 8",
    "id": "000017"
  },
  {
    "question": "The top of the tower of Babel was meant to reach into ...",
    "correctAnswer": "the heavens",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the clouds",
      "great height",
      "an invisible height"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:4",
    "id": "000018"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does the word 'Babel' mean?",
    "correctAnswer": "Confusion",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Great city",
      "Great tower",
      "Destruction"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11",
    "id": "000019"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Abram born?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ur of the Chaldeans",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Canaan",
      "Egypt",
      "Shinar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26",
    "id": "000020"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was the name of Abram's father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Terah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lot",
      "Isaac",
      "Noah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11:26",
    "id": "000021"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Abram go to Canaan?",
    "correctAnswer": "God asked him to",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There was plenty of work",
      "Family already lived there",
      "There was enough to eat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12",
    "id": "000022"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was Abram's wife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Sarai",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rebekah",
      "Rachel",
      "Zilpah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 11",
    "id": "000023"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why did Abram and Sarai go to Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "There was a famine in Canaan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "There was much money to earn",
      "They went to visit relatives",
      "It was a command from the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 12:10",
    "id": "000024"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abram and Lot return to Canaan. Where does Lot live?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the Jordan region",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On the coast",
      "In the mountains",
      "In Sodom"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19",
    "id": "000025"
  },
  {
    "question": "Sarai remains barren. Who becomes Abram's second wife?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hagar",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Zilpah",
      "Bilhah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:3",
    "id": "000026"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abram and Hagar have a son, his name is...",
    "correctAnswer": "Ishmael",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lot",
      "Isaac",
      "Jacob"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 16:11",
    "id": "000027"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Lot's wife do?",
    "correctAnswer": "She looked back while leaving Sodom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "She warned her husband Lot",
      "She stayed in Sodom",
      "She did what God asked her to do"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 19:26",
    "id": "000028"
  },
  {
    "question": "Abraham and Sarah finally have a son. How old was Abraham then?",
    "correctAnswer": "100",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "80",
      "90",
      "120"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 21:5",
    "id": "000029"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where should Abraham sacrifice Isaac?",
    "correctAnswer": "On Mount Moriah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On Mount Sinai",
      "On Mount Carmel",
      "On Mount Horeb"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22:2",
    "id": "000030"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who does Isaac marry?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rebekah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Rachel",
      "Bilhah",
      "Sarah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 24:67",
    "id": "000031"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who succeeds Moses?",
    "correctAnswer": "Joshua",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Aaron",
      "Caleb",
      "Elijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 1:1",
    "id": "000032"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Moses strike the rock?",
    "correctAnswer": "at Meribah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "at Edom",
      "at Mara",
      "at Elim"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 17:7",
    "id": "000033"
  },
  {
    "question": "After ... much of Canaan is conquered",
    "correctAnswer": "7 years",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "4 years",
      "6 years",
      "9 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua",
    "id": "000034"
  },
  {
    "question": "After Joshua's death...",
    "correctAnswer": "there is no leader anymore",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "his son succeeds him",
      "Judah succeeds him",
      "Eleazar succeeds him"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Joshua"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Joshua 24",
    "id": "000035"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was Israel's first task after Joshua's death?",
    "correctAnswer": "Fight against the remaining Canaanites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Finding a new leader",
      "The people got a period of rest",
      "Finding water sources"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 1:1",
    "id": "000036"
  },
  {
    "question": "After a long period following Joshua's death comes...",
    "correctAnswer": "a judge",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "a king",
      "an emperor",
      "a prophet"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9",
    "id": "000037"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first judge?",
    "correctAnswer": "Othniel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ehud",
      "Samgar",
      "Barak"
    ],
    "difficulty": 2,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3:9",
    "id": "000038"
  },
  {
    "question": "Under the leadership of the first judge...",
    "correctAnswer": "people serve God again",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "people serve the idols again",
      "the enemy is driven away",
      "the people become rebellious again"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 3: 9, 10",
    "id": "000039"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who are the most well-known judges?",
    "correctAnswer": "Gideon, Samson and Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Saul, David and Solomon",
      "Jephthah, Deborah and Barak",
      "Othniel, Ehud and Samgar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges",
    "id": "000040"
  },
  {
    "question": "With how many men did Gideon drive away a large army of Midianites?",
    "correctAnswer": "300 men",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1000 men",
      "100 men",
      "500 men"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 7:6",
    "id": "000041"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the last judge?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Eli",
      "Samson",
      "Jephthah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel",
    "id": "000042"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which answer does not belong. Samson may NOT ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "not marry",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "not drink wine or beer",
      "not cut his hair",
      "not touch dead bodies"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 13",
    "id": "000043"
  },
  {
    "question": "Deborah defeated the ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "Canaanites",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Midianites",
      "Ammonites",
      "Philistines"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Judges"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Judges 4",
    "id": "000044"
  },
  {
    "question": "Several judges are mentioned as heroes of faith in the Epistle to the Hebrews. Which judge is NOT mentioned in it?",
    "correctAnswer": "Deborah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Gideon",
      "Samson",
      "Samuel"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Hebrews 11",
    "id": "000045"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who leads the people after Samuel?",
    "correctAnswer": "King Saul",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "King David",
      "High Priest Eli",
      "Judge Samson"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000046"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who was the first king of Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "Saul",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Solomon",
      "Herod"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000047"
  },
  {
    "question": "Saul is anointed by Samuel ... ",
    "correctAnswer": "anointed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "crowned",
      "consecrated",
      "baptized"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 10:1",
    "id": "000048"
  },
  {
    "question": "But I hate him, because he prophesies nothing good about me, but evil. Who said that?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ahab",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Micaiah",
      "Jezebel",
      "Baasha"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 22:8",
    "id": "000049"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which time period does the story of Ruth take place?",
    "correctAnswer": "Time of Judges",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Time of Kings",
      "Exile",
      "Time of Prophets"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis",
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": null,
    "id": "000050"
  },
  {
    "question": "From which place did Elimelech and Naomi come?",
    "correctAnswer": "Bethlehem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Cana",
      "Moab"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:1",
    "id": "000051"
  },
  {
    "question": "What were the names of the women whom Naomi's sons married?",
    "correctAnswer": "Orpah and Ruth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Orpah and Rebekah",
      "Ruth and Rachel",
      "Ruth and Rebekah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:4",
    "id": "000052"
  },
  {
    "question": "How did Naomi want to be called?",
    "correctAnswer": "Mara",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Martha",
      "Mary",
      "Miriam"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 1:20",
    "id": "000053"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why was Boaz kind to Ruth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Ruth's devotion to Naomi touched him",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "He was in love with Ruth",
      "Because he was related to Naomi",
      "God asked this of him"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 2:11",
    "id": "000054"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is a kinsman-redeemer?",
    "correctAnswer": "A close relative who has the duty to help another family member",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A close relative",
      "A close relative who has much money",
      "A close relative who lives in the same place"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 3:9",
    "id": "000055"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Boaz give as proof of his redemption?",
    "correctAnswer": "His sandal",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A clay tablet",
      "His ring",
      "His coat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:7",
    "id": "000056"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of Boaz and Ruth's son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Obed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Judah",
      "Machlon",
      "Chilion"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17",
    "id": "000057"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Obed become father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jesse",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Isaac",
      "Ishmael",
      "Issachar"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ruth"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ruth 4:17",
    "id": "000058"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Jesse become father?",
    "correctAnswer": "Of King David",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Of King Solomon",
      "Of King Saul",
      "Of King Abijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 17:12",
    "id": "000059"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many wives did Elkanah have?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:2",
    "id": "000060"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the old priest think when Hannah prayed in the temple?",
    "correctAnswer": "That she was drunk",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "That she was praying earnestly",
      "That she was sad",
      "That she was tired"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:14",
    "id": "000061"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah name her son?",
    "correctAnswer": "Samuel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Samson",
      "Gideon",
      "Judah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:20",
    "id": "000062"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does Samuel mean?",
    "correctAnswer": "Asked of God",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Man of God",
      "Comforter",
      "God gives"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel",
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:17",
    "id": "000063"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Hannah bring Samuel?",
    "correctAnswer": "To Eli",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "To Jerusalem",
      "To Elijah",
      "To the temple in Jerusalem"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1: 25",
    "id": "000064"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did Hannah NOT bring with her when she brought Samuel to Eli?",
    "correctAnswer": "2 measures of barley",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3 bulls",
      "an ephah of flour",
      "a flask of wine"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 1:24",
    "id": "000065"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who thought that Samuel called him?",
    "correctAnswer": "Eli",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Hophni",
      "Phinehas",
      "the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel 3",
    "id": "000066"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which position did Samuel NOT hold in his life?",
    "correctAnswer": "King",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Prophet",
      "Priest",
      "Judge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Samuel",
    "id": "000067"
  },
  {
    "question": "How is the holy city called in Ezekiel 48?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Lord is there",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Zion",
      "Jerusalem",
      "City of God"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ezekiel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Ezekiel 48:35",
    "id": "000068"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which psalm is often called the Shepherd's Psalm?",
    "correctAnswer": "Psalm 23",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Psalm 1",
      "Psalm 25",
      "Psalm 42"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Psalms"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Psalm 23",
    "id": "000069"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do you call a male sheep?",
    "correctAnswer": "A ram",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A buck",
      "A lamb",
      "An ewe"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Genesis"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Genesis 22",
    "id": "000070"
  },
  {
    "question": "On which instrument did David often play?",
    "correctAnswer": "Harp",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Harp",
      "Flute",
      "Cymbal"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 and 2 Samuel",
    "id": "000071"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the biblical book of Proverbs?",
    "correctAnswer": "Solomon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "David",
      "Asaph",
      "Jehoshaphat"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs",
    "id": "000072"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the beginning of wisdom?",
    "correctAnswer": "The fear of the Lord",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The knowledge of the Lord",
      "The instruction of the Lord",
      "The thoughtfulness of the Lord"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 1:7",
    "id": "000073"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is God to those who walk uprightly?",
    "correctAnswer": "A Shield",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A Fortress",
      "A Refuge",
      "A High Tower"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 2:7",
    "id": "000074"
  },
  {
    "question": "With what must one honor the Lord",
    "correctAnswer": "With possessions",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "With prayer",
      "With wisdom",
      "With sincerity"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3:9",
    "id": "000075"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is more precious than rubies?",
    "correctAnswer": "Wisdom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Love",
      "Virtue",
      "Knowledge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 3: 13-15",
    "id": "000076"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who must be saved?",
    "correctAnswer": "Those in danger of death",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Those who waver",
      "Those who wander",
      "Those who live godlessly"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 24:11",
    "id": "000077"
  },
  {
    "question": "Wisdom is like ... ?",
    "correctAnswer": "a beautiful crown on the head",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "a golden necklace around the neck",
      "an ornament of knowledge",
      "a band of insight"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:9",
    "id": "000078"
  },
  {
    "question": "From where must our foot remain distant?",
    "correctAnswer": "From evil",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From the path of the wicked",
      "From uneven paths",
      "From paths of death"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 4:14",
    "id": "000079"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many things are an abomination to the Lord?",
    "correctAnswer": "Seven",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Five",
      "Six",
      "Three"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 6:16",
    "id": "000080"
  },
  {
    "question": "What covers love?",
    "correctAnswer": "All transgressions",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "All greed",
      "All unkindness",
      "All hatred"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 10:12",
    "id": "000081"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is in the house of a righteous man?",
    "correctAnswer": "A great treasure",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Love and faithfulness",
      "Understanding",
      "Knowledge"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 15:6",
    "id": "000082"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who will fall into a pit?",
    "correctAnswer": "He who digs a pit",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Who shoots burning arrows",
      "Who is wise in his own eyes",
      "Who honors a fool"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 26:27",
    "id": "000083"
  },
  {
    "question": "When does one find mercy?",
    "correctAnswer": "When one confesses and forsakes sins",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "When one is a man of understanding",
      "When one loves in secret",
      "When one does not harden his heart"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Proverbs"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Proverbs 28:13",
    "id": "000084"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where did Jesus grow up?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Capernaum"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 2:23",
    "id": "000085"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many days was Jesus tempted by the devil:",
    "correctAnswer": "40 days",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3 days",
      "10 days",
      "7 weeks"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 1:13",
    "id": "000086"
  },
  {
    "question": "On what should one build their life's house?",
    "correctAnswer": "Rock",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Sand",
      "A mountain",
      "Clay ground"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 7:25",
    "id": "000087"
  },
  {
    "question": "Of whom did Jesus say: I have not found such great faith even in Israel?",
    "correctAnswer": "The centurion",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Peter",
      "The leper",
      "The blind man"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 8:10",
    "id": "000088"
  },
  {
    "question": "Where was Matthew when Jesus called him?",
    "correctAnswer": "In the tax office",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "On the temple grounds",
      "In a tree",
      "In front of his house"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 9:9",
    "id": "000089"
  },
  {
    "question": "How big must our faith be according to Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "Like a mustard seed",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Like a mountain",
      "Like a rock",
      "Like a cedar of Lebanon"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 17:20",
    "id": "000090"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many times must we forgive each other?",
    "correctAnswer": "70 x 7 times",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7 times",
      "3 times",
      "always"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 18:22",
    "id": "000091"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who cried out: Lord, Son of David, have mercy on us",
    "correctAnswer": "2 blind men",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "10 lepers",
      "the children",
      "the lame"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Matthew 20:30",
    "id": "000092"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which tree was cursed by Jesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "The fig tree",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The olive tree",
      "The cedar",
      "The date palm"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 11:21",
    "id": "000093"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who wrote the book of Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "John",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Paul",
      "Peter",
      "Matthew"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 1:1",
    "id": "000094"
  },
  {
    "question": "To how many churches did John write a letter?",
    "correctAnswer": "7",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "6",
      "8",
      "5"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation",
    "id": "000095"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was John told to write to Ephesus?",
    "correctAnswer": "You have left your first love",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Be faithful unto death",
      "I have given you an open door",
      "And I will give you each according to your works"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Ephesians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:4",
    "id": "000096"
  },
  {
    "question": "What will Jesus give the church in Smyrna if they remain faithful?",
    "correctAnswer": "The crown of life",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A white stone",
      "A new name",
      "Hidden manna"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:10",
    "id": "000097"
  },
  {
    "question": "To which teaching did they in Pergamum cling?",
    "correctAnswer": "The teaching of Balaam",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The teaching of the Pharisees",
      "There is no resurrection",
      "The teaching of Paul"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2:14",
    "id": "000098"
  },
  {
    "question": "What woman did they allow in Thyatira?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jezebel",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "the wife of Herod",
      "The wife of Potiphar",
      "Salome"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 2: 20-23",
    "id": "000099"
  },
  {
    "question": "For what will Jesus keep the church of Philadelphia?",
    "correctAnswer": "The hour of trial",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "From poverty",
      "From diseases",
      "From spiritual decline"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3:10",
    "id": "000100"
  },
  {
    "question": "Why will Jesus spew Laodicea out of His mouth?",
    "correctAnswer": "Because they are lukewarm",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Because they are hot",
      "Because they are cold",
      "Because they are hard"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 3: 15, 16",
    "id": "000101"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was around God's throne in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "A rainbow",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A light",
      "Golden rays",
      "A cloud"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:3",
    "id": "000102"
  },
  {
    "question": "And around the throne were thrones; and on the thrones I saw ... elders sitting, clothed in white robes, and they had golden crowns on their heads. ",
    "correctAnswer": "24",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "7",
      "7 x 7",
      "3"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 4:4",
    "id": "000103"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the great multitude that no one could count have in their hands?",
    "correctAnswer": "Palm branches",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Torches",
      "Trumpets",
      "Bowls of incense"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 7:9",
    "id": "000104"
  },
  {
    "question": "What does God do with the people who come out of the great tribulation?",
    "correctAnswer": "God will wipe away every tear from their eyes",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "God will give them a new name",
      "God will seal their foreheads",
      "God will dwell among them"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21:4",
    "id": "000105"
  },
  {
    "question": "What happened when the third angel sounded?",
    "correctAnswer": "A great star, blazing like a torch, fell from the sky",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The smoke of incense with the prayers of the saints ascended",
      "There became hail and fire mixed with blood",
      "Something like a great mountain, burning with fire, was thrown into the sea"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 8:10",
    "id": "000106"
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the name of the angel of the bottomless pit in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "Abaddon",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Lucifer",
      "The dragon",
      "The beast"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 9:11",
    "id": "000107"
  },
  {
    "question": "What was John told to eat in Revelation?",
    "correctAnswer": "A little book",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "A honey cake",
      "Bread",
      "Figs"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 10:9",
    "id": "000108"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many witnesses will prophesy for 1260 days?",
    "correctAnswer": "2",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "3",
      "7",
      "12"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 11: 3-12",
    "id": "000109"
  },
  {
    "question": "And the woman fled to the ... , where she had a place prepared by God",
    "correctAnswer": "wilderness",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "temple",
      "mountains",
      "city"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "fitb",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 12:6",
    "id": "000110"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many bowls of wrath are there?",
    "correctAnswer": "Seven",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Three",
      "Five",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 5,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 16",
    "id": "000111"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which city comes down from heaven?",
    "correctAnswer": "The new Jerusalem",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The city of God",
      "The city with many dwellings",
      "That city which has foundations"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 21: 1-4",
    "id": "000112"
  },
  {
    "question": "What do the Spirit and the Bride say?",
    "correctAnswer": "Come",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Amen",
      "Hallelujah",
      "I am the Alpha and the Omega"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Revelation"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Revelation 22:17",
    "id": "000113"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many letters are there from Paul to the Corinthians?",
    "correctAnswer": "Two",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "One",
      "Three",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Corinthians",
      "2 Corinthians"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": " 1 and 2 Corinthians",
    "id": "000114"
  },
  {
    "question": "How many people did Jesus raise from the dead?",
    "correctAnswer": "Three",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "One",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Gospels",
    "id": "000115"
  },
  {
    "question": "For approximately how many years did Jesus preach?",
    "correctAnswer": "Three",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Two",
      "One",
      "Four"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "In the Gospels",
    "id": "000116"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city did they drive Jesus out of town, to the edge of the mountain, to throw Him into the abyss?",
    "correctAnswer": "Nazareth",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Bethlehem",
      "Samaria"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 4:29",
    "id": "000117"
  },
  {
    "question": "In which city was Bartimaeus sitting by the gate begging?",
    "correctAnswer": "Jericho",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Jerusalem",
      "Samaria",
      "Capernaum"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Mark 10:46",
    "id": "000118"
  },
  {
    "question": "To whom was it asked: Do you also understand what you are reading?",
    "correctAnswer": "The Ethiopian eunuch",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Philip",
      "Peter",
      "Saul"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 8:30",
    "id": "000119"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which island did Paul and Barnabas visit on their first missionary journey?",
    "correctAnswer": "Cyprus",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Crete",
      "Malta",
      "Sicily"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 13:4",
    "id": "000120"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which king became severely ill, a terminal illness?",
    "correctAnswer": "Hezekiah",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Ahaz",
      "Manasseh",
      "Jehudah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Hezekiah 20:1",
    "id": "000121"
  },
  {
    "question": "After fleeing from Queen Jezebel, where did Elijah flee to the cave? Which one?",
    "correctAnswer": "The cave on Mount Horeb",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The cave of Machpelah",
      "The cave of Adullam",
      "The caves of Zephaniah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "1 Kings"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "1 Kings 19",
    "id": "000122"
  },
  {
    "question": "What did the Israelites NOT take with them from the Egyptians when they left Egypt?",
    "correctAnswer": "Food",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Gold",
      "Silver",
      "Clothing"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Exodus"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Exodus 3:22",
    "id": "000123"
  },
  {
    "question": "How long was Paul imprisoned in Caesarea during the time of Felix and Festus?",
    "correctAnswer": "2 years",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "1.5 years",
      "2.5 years",
      "3 years"
    ],
    "difficulty": 3,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts",
    "id": "000124"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which deacon was stoned in Jerusalem?",
    "correctAnswer": "Stephen",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Philip",
      "Timon",
      "Nicholas"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "Acts"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "Acts 7: 54 - 60",
    "id": "000125"
  },
  {
    "question": "Which son wanted to push David from the throne?",
    "correctAnswer": "Absalom",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "Joab",
      "Amnon",
      "Adonijah"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [
      "2 Samuel"
    ],
    "biblicalReference": "2 Samuel 15",
    "id": "000126"
  },
  {
    "question": "Who were the first to visit Jesus after His birth?",
    "correctAnswer": "The shepherds",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "The wise men",
      "King Herod",
      "Zacharias and Elizabeth"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 2: 8-20",
    "id": "000127"
  },
  {
    "question": "10 lepers were healed by Jesus. Who came back to thank Him?",
    "correctAnswer": "A Samaritan",
    "incorrectAnswers": [
      "An Israelite",
      "A Jew",
      "A Tax Collector"
    ],
    "difficulty": 1,
    "type": "mc",
    "categories": [],
    "biblicalReference": "Luke 17:11-19",
    "id": "000128"
  }
]